hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says solve for x and it gives us XM + Dy
= a n + xth we got to get both X's to
the same side of the equation so I'm
going to subtract xth from both sides
and then while we're at it this Dy does
not have an X in it so we want to move
it to the other side and we can do that
by subtracting Dy from both sides this
positive Dy and negative Dy will cancel
each other out and the positive XT and
the negative XT will cancel each other
out so we're left with X Maus xth = a
minus Dy now all the X's are on the same
side and every term has an X in it so
let's factor out that X when we Factor
the X out of this first term it's an MA
that's remaining and when we Factor the
X out of this term it's a th that's
remaining next to get the X all by
itself we're going to divide both sides
by ma minus th the ma minus th's on top
and bottom will divide each other out
and that leaves us with X = a nus dy
over ma minus th this is the answer to
our question let's put a box around it
how exciting